

Senior 3D & Graphic Designer with 7+ years of experience in management of the complete design process from conceptualization to delivery. Expert at interdepartmental coordination and communication. Skilled with Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Aftereffects, InDesign). Ability to work with variety of 3D Designing software like Maya, 3ds Max enhancing overall output and achieving companies' all design requirements.

# Vinay Kumar Saini

Phone:

+91 9398397923

E-Mail:

vinnu022@gmail.com

Website:

www.flyingbird3dstudio.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinaykumar-saini-654390a1/

### **Skill Highlights**

Adobe XD UI & UX

Link 1: Design 1
Link 2: Design 2

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Aftereffects
- Adobe InDesign
- Autodesk Maya

Link 3: Showreel

Autodesk 3DsMax

#### **3D/Graphic Design Samples**

Link 3: Sample Designs

#### Languages

English, Hindi, Telugu

## **Experience**

06/2020 to Present

#### Vollmond Innovations & Social Entrepreneurs Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad

- Cooperate with developers to create clean UI & UX interfaces
  - and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Design project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Complete detailed designing tasks for front end developers and Internal websites, logos

10/2018 to 05/2020

#### Rachnoutsav Events Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad

- Designed events & planned using 3D & 2D while managing all event project elements within allotted time limits.
- Maintained social media works like videos, flyers, logos Brochures etc.

06/2017 to 08/2018

#### **RVR PRO Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad**

Design all required elements for event using maya & max

04/2016 to 05/2017

#### **Bestbus Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad**

• Coordinate with marketing manager & design all required elements for Ads

08/2015 to 05/2016

#### Sync Process Soft Tech Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad

 Complete detailed designing tasks for front end developers and internal websites as well as design logos

### **Education**

Bachelor of Commerce: Computers- 2014

Osmania University, Hyderabad

64%

Intermediate: CEC- 2011

New Era Junior College, Hyderabad

70%

Secondary School Certification (SSC) 2009

Krishnaveni Talent School, Mancherial

65%

### **Certifications:** Diploma in Visual Media (DVM)

# **Projects**

Docstech App

https://www.docsteth.com/

A Global Consortium Medical Doctors. An Exclusive Platform for Doctors A healthcare eco-system powered by Social Networking.

#### Medxperts

https://www.medxperts.in/

Medxperts Started with an idea to create globally accessible and reliable patient centric care with core Focus on educating the patients and empowering them with informed decision making.

A self-service application for patients, doctors, hospitals to access services, medical records & understand their care plan.

NeonatAl

https://www.neonatai.com/

Developed for Neonatal Care.

NeonatAl is a useful application to residents, post-graduates, nursing staff, pediatricians and neonatologists taking care of sick as well as healthy newborns. It simplifies the care process and empowers the health staff in improving quality care. It has calculators, checklists, infographics and scores/charts

### **Personal Details**

FATHER NAME: Laxman Rao Saini
DATE OF BIRTH: 20-10-1992
MARITAL STATUS: Married
NATIONALITY: Indian

HOBBIES: Listening Music

ADDRESS: Kailash Hills, Kukatpally, Hyderabad.